So in the last video,
لذا في الفيديو الأخير،
we talked about how relying on mathematical theorems,
تحدثنا عن كيفية الاعتماد على النظريات الرياضية،
like the central limit theorem leads to
مثل نظرية الحد المركزي التي تؤدي إلى
gaps in whether we've achieved a large enough sample size or,
ثغرات في ما إذا كنا قد حققنا حجم عينة كبير بما فيه الكفاية،
which statistics the theorem applies to,
أو بشأن الإحصاءات التي تنطبق عليها النظرية،
and that instead of relying on theorems we could simulate the sampling distribution.
وذلك بدلاً من الاعتماد على النظريات التي يمكننا من خلالها محاكاة توزيع العينات.
This introduces a technique known as bootstrapping.
هذا يقدم تقنية تعرف باسم أخذ العينات.
Bootstrapping in statistics, means sampling with replacement.
أخذ العينات في الإحصاءات، يعني أخذ العينات مع الاستبدال.
If we want to bootstrap sample five individuals from this group,
إذا كنا نريد أخذ عينة من خمسة أفراد من هذه المجموعة،
we could randomly sample these five here.
يمكننا بشكل عشوائي أخذ عينة من هذه الخمسة هنا.
However, in bootstrap sampling,
على الرغم من ذلك، في أخذ العينات،
we are sampling with replacement.
نأخذ العينات مع الاستبدال.
So we could actually end up sampling these four,
لذا يمكننا في نهاية المطاف أخذ عينات من هذه الأربعة،
and this one might end up being sampled again.
وقد ينتهي الأمر باختبار هذه العينة مرة أخرى.
We could look at this a bit slower.
يمكن أن ننظر إلى هذا بشكل أبطأ قليلا.
In sampling, we might end up choosing this individual.
في أخذ العينات، قد ينتهي بنا المطاف باختيار هذا الفرد.
And immediately after choosing it as a part of the sample,
وعلى الفور بعد اختياره كجزء من العينة،
it goes back to potentially be chosen again.
فإنه يعود لاحتمالية اختياره مرة أخرى.
It is possible, though unlikely,
من الممكن، على الرغم من أنه من غير المحتمل،
in bootstrap sampling to choose the same individual for every random draw.
أخذ عينة لاختيار نفس الشخص لكل رسم عشوائي.
We could end up choosing this individual or any of these five times in a row.
قد ينتهي بنا الأمر إلى اختيار هذا الفرد أو أي من هذه الخمس مرات في صف.
After a little more practice with this,
بعد المزيد من التمرين مع هذا،
you'll be ready to apply bootstrapping to simulate sampling distributions.
ستكون مستعدًا لتطبيق أخذ العينات لمحاكاة توزيعات العينات.